Some people
are just natural-born worriers.
My mother, for example,
could whip herself into a frenzy,
even if/ were sitting on my bed
doing nothing.
Shelly?
Everything okay?
Hunky-dory. Why?
Well, you're kind of dressed like
you kidnapped yourself.
Oh, I'm trying to block out sensory input.
I hit a roadblock determining
whether virtual particles have a fixed mass
or violate momentum conservation.
But then I remembered
that Nikola Tesla believed
that isolation is where ideas are born.
Who's Nikola Tesla?
One of the most prolific scientists
of the 20th century.
Okay.
And...
Just out of curiosity, how isolated was he?
Oh, highly.
He found human contact revolting.
Well, that's kind of a lonely way to live,
don't you think?
Well, he wasn't entirely alone.
At the end of his life, he became
good friends with a brown pigeon.
See you.
J“ nobody else is stronger than I am j“
j“ yesterday I moved a mountain j“
j“ I bet I could be your hero j“
j“ I am a mighty little man j“
have you heard from Dr. Sturgis at all?
Nope.
Can you believe the hospital's
still holding him for observation?
Can't you?
Well...
I think I just felt a neutrino.
That one went right through my pants.
You have goosegrass!
And you can't have a nice lawn
if you have goosegrass.
I mean...
I'm worried about him.
I don't know how serious this is.
The whole year you were together,
did you see any, um...
Warning signs?
No. Not really.
I just thought he was another, you know,
cute, quirky egghead like Sheldon.
Speaking of which,
when are you gonna tell Sheldon
the truth about John?
Mm. When the time is right.
So he still thinks he's being treated
for mono?
I had to come up with something
contagious so he wouldn't want to visit.
Smart.
Thank you.
You're good at lying.
You should do it more often.
I like your earrings.
Oh, my, he's gonna be trapped!
All right, see, when you get tackled
in your own end zone,
the other team gets two points
and the ball. That's called a safety.
I thought one of the players was a safety.
Well, that's true too.
I'm confused.
Now you know how I feel when you talk
about teenage mutant ninja turtles.
What's confusing?
Everything you need
to know is in the title.
Dad, how would you like to be rich?
Go away.
Aren't you even a little curious?
Does it involve me giving you money?
Yeah, but then I give you more money back.
How much more?
Way more.
You gotta get in on this.
Thanks. I'm not interested.
You're gonna regret it.
Show me.
Texas snow globes.
Ooh...
The card store on magnolia
is going out of business.
They're selling these for $1 each.
I sell them for 5 and the money rolls in.
Does it worry you that the store selling
these things is going out of business?
You have no vision.
- Can I get back to the game?
- Fine.
I don't need your money. I have my own.
- So why are we having this conversation?
- I'd rather lose your money than mine.
Vision.
I've always felt
the world of subatomic particles
would make an excellent video game.
Fortunately, thanks to my brain,
I've been playing it for years.
You cheeky little muon,
you know you don't belong there.
Don't look at me. He's your kid.
Someone likes snow globes.
I hope so. I don't want them.
Okay.
What do we got here?
Farmhouse kitchen...
Garfield hangs out...
The complete guide
to your child's mental...
Oh, look, that cute little book light,
I'll get that too.
Okay.
You still want the crazy kid book, right?
Okay, 52 Texas snow globes
comes to $55.25.
- Can't you do any better?
- What do you mean?
You're going out of business
and I'm buying them all. Give me a break.
Okay, $50.
-Thirty -forty.
- Thirty-five.
- Deal.
No, wait, 32.
Thirty-three.
Thirty-five.
George.
Hey, that's clever.
I'm reading this book
about mental problems,
and I'm worried it sounds like Sheldon.
Well, stop reading the book.
Shelly and Dr. Sturgis have a lot
in common, and look what happened.
What, you mean like how he went to...
As a society,
we've made strides
in how we discuss psychological issues.
Thirty years ago in east Texas,
let's just say we hadn't.
Cuckoo, cuckoo! Heh, heh.
Hey. That could be your son one day.
Just because they're both super-smart
doesn't mean that they're the same person.
I mean, sturgis was in love with your mom,
so clearly he was nuts from the get-go.
You're not helping.
I'm not wrong, either.
Love you.
Why aren't you also driving missy
to school?
I thought it might be nice for us to chat.
About missy? She is a bit much, isn't she?
Here's a question for you:
Do you ever see or hear things
that other people can't?
Oh, all the time.
Right now, the car antenna is vibrating
at the same frequency
as the pistons in the motor.
It's quite irritating, but you know me,
I don't complain.
I meant more like things
that aren't actually there.
Ah. Isn't that the fundamental question
of modern metaphysics?
What is actually there?
This is fun.
Missy should ride with dad more often.
Let me try this a different way.
Do you ever feel paranoid,
like people are out to get you?
I'm a 10-year-old in high school.
People are out to get me.
That's fair.
I just think if I was having these
feelings, that might be scary, right?
I suppose so.
And this is something
that's been concerning you?
Maybe.
Lately.
A little. But the important thing is
that we can always talk about
this kind of thing with each other.
Do you have any books on mental health?
Sure. Why?
I believe my mother is unraveling.
We have a few books on mental illness
you might find helpful.
This one's a good place to start.
- Have you read it?
- Read it, lived it,
made the mistake of talking about it
on a date.
Sure. Walk away.
They all do.
Who is it?
- Georgie Cooper.
- Who?
- I'm your neighbor.
- The one with the chickens?
The ones with that weird, smart kid?
Yeah, that's my brother.
Neither do I, sir.
What do you want?
I was wondering if you'd like to buy
one of...
You didn't even see what I was selling.
What?
Texas snow globes.
Dang it.
It's pretty.
Why would I want that?
Well, um...
Because it's Texas
and everybody in Texas loves Texas?
Dang it.
And if you act now, you can have
this beautiful, limited edition keepsake
in your home for the low, low price
of only $5.
I hope you know
- I'm missing people's court right now.
- But with Christmas coming,
this would make
an excellent stocking-stuffer.
Well, you're my grandson
and I love you.
So it hurts me to do this.
Dang it.
Oh!
Oh, dear.
Oh, no.
Sorry I gave you the boot before.
- Does that mean you'll buy one now?
- No.
You didn't sell a single snow globe?
Don't give your brother a hard time.
He took some initiative and I admire that.
- Thank you.
- I mean, the snow globes were silly,
- but I bet your next idea will be great.
- They're not silly.
I'm glad you feel that way,
because you got 50 of them.
I'm gonna sell them all
just to prove you wrong.
Well, now I know it's a peeing contest
between you and your daddy, I'll take two.
Well, all right. Mom, you're not crazy
about dad. Wanna buy a snow globe?
Enough.
And I don't like us
making fun of each other.
We're family, and this should be a place that
is safe, where we can talk about anything.
I agree.
Now, let's just say grace.
Thank you, god,
for this food we are about to receive,
and bless the hands that prepared it.
And please,
keep us all in good health, body, and mind.
- Why are you looking at me?
- I'm not. Amen.
Amen.
Hello?
Oh, baby.
What are you doing up?
I couldn't sleep. Why are you up?
Same.
Do you have insomnia from anxiety?
Is that what you have?
What are you anxious about?
Honestly, your mental health.
Me? Why?
Well, you seem preoccupied lately,
and you were asking me
all those questions in the car.
I was just letting you know
that if you were having any problems,
you can come to me with them.
You think I have mental problems?
Well, not problems.
I'm just worried about your future,
and when I see you moving subatomic
particles around in the air, that...
Subatomic particles are real.
You talk to an invisible man in the sky who
grants wishes. If anyone's mental, it's you.
Okay, now you are over the line.
You apologize.
What the hell's going on?
- Nothing, it's fine.
- Mom thinks that I'm crazy.
I thought we weren't
supposed to say stuff like that.
- Mother.
- Yes?
Is it okay if I use a
knife to butter my toast
or are you worried
I'll do something crazy with it?
You can butter your own toast.
Oh, good, you see the toast too.
I was afraid I was imagining it.
- Sheldon.
- All right, that's enough.
- What's going on?
- Nothing, everything's fine.
I'll tell you later.
My mother believes I'm mentally unstable.
And since there's a genetic component
and I'm her child, I suppose it's possible.
I know you're angry right now,
but you will not be disrespectful.
You know, fits of rage
are a classic sign of psychosis.
Oh, you haven't seen fits of rage yet.
I said that's enough.
Both of y'all are acting like lunatics.
- You up to speed?
- I think I got it.
I already accepted Jesus in my heart.
No, I'm selling these Texas snow globes.
I have enough crap in my house.
Crap?
You love Texas, right?
Well, sure.
And who doesn't like snow?
Sleds and snowball fights.
I remember it snowed hard here
once when I was a kid.
- That must've been amazing.
- It was.
They canceled school. Me and my brother
build a snow fort in the backyard.
That's cool.
My brother and I love doing stuff together.
We're really close.
I hadn't thought about that day
in a long time.
Well, what if that memory...
Was just one shake away?
- How much?
- Five dollars.
Fine. I'll take it.
- How about you get one for your brother?
- I don't know.
He married some yankee gal,
moved to Connecticut.
But he's still your brother.
Oh, what the hell.
She's gonna leave him at some point.
I don't see the point of this.
I just don't think it could hurt
for us to talk to someone.
But I could be at home right now
wearing a blindfold, mittens,
and nose plug doing something important.
You know, maybe you should mention
the blindfold and mittens to the doctor.
Or maybe I'll mention how you think that
god speaks to you,
because I find that concerning.
He does speak to me,
and right now he's saying
I should wash your mouth out with soap.
Violent fantasies.
Interesting.
J“ salesman, where you gonna go sell
all of your goods today... j“
Mrs. Ebner, do you remember where you
were the last time it snowed in medford?
We didn't have a carrot
for the snowman's nose,
so can you believe we used a hot dog?
That must've been a sight.
I was with my grandchildren.
They had never seen snow before.
I taught them to make snow angels.
Little angels making little angels.
Can't put a price on memories.
- But I am running a special. Two for 8.
- Hm...
Hey, little Princess.
This is called "snow."
She likes it.
So naturally,
I was concerned about his well-being,
and was keeping an eye on him
just to be safe.
- It's called being neurotic.
- It's called being a good mother.
This is healthy.
Communication is the cornerstone...
I'm behaving no differently than ever.
Why are you suddenly so worried
about me?
That is a valid question.
Has anything changed recently?
- Well...
- Maybe it's hormonal.
When does menopause typically begin?
It is not my hormones.
Well, it certainly isn't mine.
I'm showing no signs of puberty.
You know, sometimes mothers
look for issues with their children
- so they can feel more needed.
- Okay, now we're getting somewhere.
That is not what's happening.
Well, then what is happening?
Baby, there's something I need to tell you.
Dr. Sturgis is not in the kind of hospital
you think he is.
What kind of hospital is he in?
The psychiatric kind.
- Why, what's going on?
- He was having some issues,
but he's getting the help he needs,
and I'm sure he's gonna be fine.
And you think since he and I are
both gifted, I'm going to end up like him.
Well, it...
It crossed my mind.
Sheldon, you're my baby.
It is my job to worry about you.
I can't help it.
I'm sorry I caused you so much concern.
I'm not.
See how valuable
a little communication can be?
You do not take credit for this.
And the turtle eating
the pizza is Leonardo.
How can you tell?
He's wearing blue.
Dad, remember my silly idea?
Guess what? It's snowing.
Jn show, si'iow, show, show, showj“
j“ snow, snow, snow
snow, snow, snow, snowj“
f jing, ling, ling, ling/”i179 f